Register of the Socialist Workers Party records
Hoover Institution Archives
- GELFAND VS. SMITH ET AL. FILE, 1979-1990
  - Background material (Box 99)
    - Workers League/Workers Revolutionary Party and related publications
      - The Carleton Twelve, 1981 (Folder 8)
      - Edward Heisler, the SWP and the Assassination of Tom Henehan, 1981 (Folder 9)
      - Healy, Gerry, Studies in Dialectical Materialism, 1982 (Folder 10)
      - North, David, Class War at Phelps Dodge, 1983 (Folder 11)
      - The Confession of Sylvia Franklin, 1983 (Folder 12)
      - A Provocateur Attacks Trotskyism, 1983 (Folder 13)
      - The Gelfand Case: A Legal History of the Exposure of U.S. Government Agents in the Leadership of the Socialist Workers Party, 1985
        - Volume 1 (Folder 14)
        - Volume 2 (Folder 15)
      - Gelfand, Alan, In Defense of the Gelfand Case: An Open Letter to Cliff Slaughter, 1987 (Folder 16)
      - Newspaper and journal articles
        - 1964-1965 (Folder 17)
        - 1972 (Folder 18)
        - 1975 (Box 102, Folder 1)
        - 1976 (Folder 2)
        - 1977 (Folder 3)
        - 1978 (Folder 4)
        - 1979 (Folder 5)
        - 1980 (Folder 6)
        - 1981 (Folder 7)
        - 1982 (Folder 8)
        - 1983 (Folder 9)
        - 1984 (Folder 10)
        - 1985 (Folder 11)
        - 1986 (Folder 12)
        - 1987 (Folder 13)
        - 1988 (Folder 14)
        - 1989 (Folder 15)
        - 1990 (Folder 16)
    - Subject file
      - Budenz, Louis Francis. Clippings, journal articles, and Congressional testimony, 1945-1952 (Folder 17)
      - Doxsee, Sylvia [Sylvia Franklin; Sylvia Caldwell]. Marriage license, reports and correspondence of internal party investigation, grand jury testimony, notes, and printed matter, 1933-1977 (Folder 18)
      - Hansen, Joseph. Correspondence, memoranda, Political Committee minutes, notes, and printed matter, 1937-1980 (Folder 19)
      - Healy, Gerry. Correspondence, memoranda, notes, and printed matter, 1959-1990 (Box 103, Folder 1)
      - Los Angeles (Calif.) Police Dept. Public Disorder Intelligence Division
        - Board of Police Commissioners documents. Operational and procedural guidelines, reports, and hearing transcripts, 1976-1983 (Folder 2)
        - Gibby, Rickey C. Undercover police reports, 1975-1979 (Folder 3)
        - Parisi, Vincent. Undercover police reports, 1975-1979 (Folder 4)
        - Pfaelzer, Mariana R. Draft articles, clippings, and hearing transcripts re involvement as police commissioner, 1975-1983 (Folder 5)
        - Printed matter. Newsletters, clippings, and printed articles, 1980-1983 (Folder 6)
        - Coalition against Police Abuse et al. vs. Gates et al. Legal complaints, released discovered documents, and correspondence, 1981 (Folder 7)
      - Robins, Harold. Obituary and letters, 1988 (Folder 8)
      - Zborowski, Mark. Correspondence, notes, Congressional testimony, and printed articles, 1939-1976 (Folder 9)
- AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL, 1937-1978
  Photographs and phonotape cassettes.
  - Photographs relating to Fourth International activities in China, Great Britain, Trinidad, and Zaire, 1937-1966 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Phonotape cassettes from Gelfand vs. Smith et al. trial
    - Exhibit no. 13 (Alan Gelfand-Peter Camejo conversation, 1976) (Folder 11)
    - Exhibit no. 19 (Alan Gelfand-Peter Camejo conversation, 1978) (Folder 12)
- SERIAL ISSUES AND SERIAL ISSUE INDEXES, 1928-1991 (Box 104-112)
  Issues and indexes of serial publications reflecting views of the Socialist Workers Party and its predecessors Indexes, 1928-1991. Contents lists, author indexes, country indexes and subject indexes.
  - Militant (New York City) (Box 104-111)
    - 1928-1929 (Folder 104: 1)
    - 1930 (Folder 104: 2)
    - 1931 (Folder 104: 3)
    - 1932 (Folder 104: 4)
    - 1933 (Folder 104: 5)
    - 1934 (continued by New Militant) (Folder 104: 6)
    - 1943 (Folder 104: 7)
    - 1944 (Folder 104: 8)
    - 1944 (contd.) (Folder 105: 1)
    - 1945 (Folder 105: 2)
    - 1946 (Folder 105: 3)
    - 1947 (Folder 105: 4)
    - 1948 (Folder 105: 5)
    - 1949 (Folder 105: 6)
    - 1951 (Folder 106: 1)
    - 1953 (Folder 106: 2)
    - 1956 (Folder 106: 3)
    - 1957 (Folder 106: 4)
    - 1958 (Folder 106: 5)
    - 1959 (Folder 106: 6)
    - 1965 (Folder 106: 7)
    - 1966 (Folder 106: 8)
    - 1967 (Folder 106: 9)
    - 1968 (Folder 107: 1)
    - 1969 (Folder 107: 2-3)
    - 1970 (Folder 107: 4-5)
    - 1971 (Folder 107: 6)
    - 1972 (Folder 108: 1)
    - 1973 (Folder 108: 2)
    - 1974 (Folder 108: 3)
    - 1975 (Folder 108: 4)
    - 1976 (Folder 108: 5)
    - 1977 (Folder 108: 6-7)
    - 1977 (contd.) (Folder 109: 1)
    - 1978 (Folder 109: 2)
    - 1979 (Folder 109: 3)
    - 1980 (Folder 109: 4)
    - 1981 (Folder 109: 5)
    - 1982 (Folder 109: 6)
    - 1983 (Folder 110: 1)
    - 1984 (Folder 110: 2)
    - 1985 (Folder 110: 3)
    - 1986 (Folder 110: 4)
    - 1987 (Folder 110: 5)
    - 1988 (Folder 110: 6)
    - 1989 (Folder 111: 1)
  - New Militant (New York City), 1934-1936 (continued by Socialist Appeal) (Folder 111: 2)
  - Socialist Appeal (New York City) (Box 111)
    - 1935-1937 (Folder 111: 3)
    - 1938 (Folder 111: 4)
    - 1939 (continued by Militant) (Folder 111: 5)
  - Labor Action (San Francisco), 1936-1937 (Folder 111: 6)
  - Perspectiva mundial (New York City) (Box 111)
    - 1977 (Folder 111: 7)
    - 1978 (Folder 111: 8)
    - 1979 (Folder 111: 9)
    - 1980 (Folder 111: 10)
    - 1981 (Folder 111: 11)
    - 1982 (Folder 111: 12)
    - 1985 (Folder 111: 13)
    - 1986 (Folder 111: 14)
    - 1987 (Folder 111: 15)
    - 1988 (Folder 111: 16)
    - 1989 (Folder 111: 17)
    - 1990 (Folder 111: 18)
    - 1991 (Folder 111: 19)
  - Serial issues, 1934-1937 (Box 112)
    - New International (New York City), Bound volume, 1934-1936 (Folder 112: 1)
    - Socialist Appeal (New York City), Bound volume, 1937 (Folder 112: 2)
- ADDENDUM, 1929-1998 (Boxes 113-136)
  - Fourth International File, 1953-1985.
    Fourth International World Congress documents, and documentary publications and working materials for proposed documentary publications about the Socialist Workers Party’s relations with the Fourth International
    - Pseudonyms. Correlation lists of pseudonyms and real names (Box-folder 113: 1)
    - J. Yankel review of Rodolphe Prager, Les congrès de la IVe Internationale, Volume II, L’Internationale dans la guerre, 1940-1946, with English translation, 1982 (Box-folder 113: 2)
    - Document lists, 1940-1951 (Box-folder 113: 3)
    - Proposed documentary publication, 1940-1946. Draft introduction (Box-folder 113: 4)
    - Pablo split, 1953. Typed copies of documents (Box-folder 113: 5)
    - Pabloism correspondence, 1956-1957. Typed copies (Box-folder 113: 6)
    - The Struggle to Reunify the Fourth International, 1954-1963. Education for Socialists bulletin series, 1977-1978
      - Volume I. The First Parity Commission and Peng Shu-tse’s “Pabloism Reviewed” (Box-folder 113: 7)
      - Volume II. “De-Stalinization,” the Hungarian Revolution, and World Trotskyism: Documents, 1955-57 (Box-folder 113: 8)
      - Volume III. How Healy and Pablo Blocked Reunification: Documents, 1956-58, plus Documents on Algeria and Ceylon (Box-folder 113: 9)
      - Volume IV. “Deep Entryism” and Pablo’s Anti-Unity Offensive: Documents, 1958-1960, plus Documents from India and Japan (Box-folder 113: 10)
    - “Reunification Struggle.” Typed copies of documents for proposed continuation of bulletin series
      - Section XX. “A Decisive Convergence: The Cuban Revolution” (Box-folder 113: 11)
      - Section XXI. “The Fight with Healy Opens Up” (Box-folder 113: 12)
      - Section XXIII. “Peng Shu-tse and the SLL Debate Unity” (Box-folder 113: 13)
      - Section XXIV. “Conflicting Views on World Events and International Tasks” (Box-folder 113: 14)
      - Section XXV. “Letters from Latin America by Joseph Hansen” (Box-folder 113: 15)
      - Section XXVI. “’The Permanent Factionalist Can Never Become a Party Builder’: Healy Seeks Allies in the SWP” (Box-folder 113: 16)
      - Section XXVII. “Steps toward Reunification” (Box-folder 114: 1)
      - Section XXVIII. “Divisions in the International Secretariat” (Box-folder 114: 2)
      - Section XXIX. “A Debate in the SWP” (Box-folder 114: 3)
      - Section XXX. “The Parity Commission Begins Functioning” (Box-folder 114: 4)
      - Section XXXI. “A Debate among Adherents of the International Committee” (Box-folder 114: 5)
      - Section XXXII. “A Split among Healy’s American Supporters” (Box-folder 114: 6)
      - Section XXXIII. “The Political Basis of Reunification” (Box-folder 114: 7)
      - Section XXXIV. “A Final Effort to Forestall Healy’s Split” (Box-folder 114: 8)
      - Section XXXV. “The Reunification of the Fourth International” (Box-folder 114: 9)
    - 7th (Reunification) World Congress (1963)
      - Minutes (Box-folder 115: 1)
      - Resolutions (Box-folder 115: 2)
    - 8th World Congress (1965)
      - Minutes (Box-folder 115: 3)
      - Resolutions (Box-folder 115: 4)
    - 9th World Congress (1969)
      - Minutes (Box-folder 115: 5)
      - Resolutions (Box-folder 115: 6)
    - 10th World Congress (1974)
      - Minutes (Box-folder 115: 7)
      - Resolutions (Box-folder 115: 8)
    - Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circular letters, 1974 (Box-folder 115: 9)
    - 11th World Congress (1979)
      - Minutes (Box-folder 115: 10)
      - Resolutions (English) (Box-folder 115: 11)
      - Resolutions (Spanish) (Box-folder 115: 12)
    - 12th World Congress (1985)
      - Minutes (Box-folder 116: 1)
      - Resolutions (English) (Box-folder 116: 2)
      - Resolutions (French) (Box-folder 116: 3)
  - Geographical File, 1929-1995. (Box 116-124)
    Correspondence, notes, memoranda, resolutions, draft articles, position papers, internal bulletins and printed matter relating to Socialist Workers Party relations with organizations in specific countries and with Fourth International debates regarding specific countries
    - Afghanistan. Debate within Fourth International on Soviet intervention in Afghanistan, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 116: 4)
    - Albania. Draft article by Jonathan Silberman, 1992 (Box-folder 116: 5)
    - Algeria
      - Front de Libération Nationale Tripoli Program, 1962 (Box-folder 116: 6)
      - Documents on Self-Management (Auto-Gestion), 1963 (Box-folder 116: 7)
    - Angola
      - Movimento Popular de Libertacão de Angola relations with the SWP, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 116: 8)
      - Leninist-Trotskyist Faction resolution, 1976 (Box-folder 116: 9)
    - Australia
      - Socialist Workers Party of Australia relations with the SWP, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 116: 10)
      - Socialist Workers Party of Australia split, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 116: 11)
    - Brazil
      - Trotskyist groups, ca. 1971-1982 (Box-folder 117: 1)
      - Partido dos Trabalhadores documents, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 117: 2)
      - Movimento dos Trabalhadores Sem Terra. Report on trip to Brazil, 1995 (Box-folder 117: 3)
    - Chile. Chart of leftist groups, circa 1970 (Box-folder 117: 4)
    - China
      - How Stalin-Bucharin Destroyed the Chinese Revolution: A Letter by Chen Duxiu, 1929. Typed copy (Box-folder 117: 5)
      - Trotskyism, 1930s-1940s. Printed articles (Box-folder 117: 6)
        1990
      - Cultural Revolution. Includes draft resolution by George Novack, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 117: 7)
    - Ethiopia. Bibliography on Ethiopia-Somalia conflict and Jack Barnes notes, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 117: 8)
    - France
      - Mai 1968: Première phase de la révolution socialiste francaise (Box-folder 117: 9)
      - Thomas Sankara Association Internationale correspondence re Burkina Faso, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 117: 10)
      - Ligue Communiste. Trip report on founding of organization, 1989 (Box-folder 117: 11)
    - Germany. Fourth International articles, 1945-1953 (Box-folder 117: 12)
    - Great Britain
      - Bevanism. Includes George Novack report and retrospective letter, 1952-1980 (Box-folder 117: 13)
      - Socialist League documents, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 117: 14)
      - Socialist League minority resolution, 1987 (Box-folder 117: 15)
      - Communist League founding conference documents, 1988 (Box-folder 117: 16)
      - Communist League Central Committee plenum report, 1989 (Box-folder 118: 1)
      - Communist League. Jack Barnes trip report, 1989 (Box-folder 118: 2)
    - Iceland. Communist League founding meeting documents, 1988 (Box-folder 118: 3)
    - India. S. B. Kolpe interview transcript on Trotskyism in India, 1930s-1940s (Box-folder 118: 4)
    - Israel
      - Correspondence with Israeli Trotskyists. Includes Gus Horowitz-Michel Warschawsky correspondence
        - 1972-1975 (Box-folder 118: 5)
        - 1976-1979 (Box-folder 118: 6)
        - 1980-1988 (Box-folder 118: 7)
      - Palestine debate in Fourth International, 1973 (Box-folder 118: 8)
      - Lebanon invasion, 1982 (Box-folder 118: 9)
        Debate in Fourth International
      - Israeli imperialism draft article by Dave Frankel, 1982 (Box-folder 118: 10)
      - Palestine debate in Fourth International, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 118: 11)
      - Campaign to End Aid to Israel advertisement in New York Times, 1988 (Box-folder 118: 12)
    - Korea
      - Post-World War II history. Articles, 1950-1990 (Box-folder 119: 1)
      - Correspondence with Workers Party of Korea and North Korean government. Includes Jack Barnes-Kim Il Sung correspondence
        - 1989-1990 (Box-folder 119: 2)
        - 1991 (Box-folder 119: 3)
        - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 119: 4)
      - Trip to North Korea by Jack Barnes and Margaret Jayko, 1990
        - General (Box-folder 119: 5)
        - Jack Barnes report and SWP discussion (Box-folder 119: 6)
        - Pyongyang Declaration, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 119: 7)
    - Latin America
      - Frente Continental de Mujeres contra la Intervención meetings, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 119: 8)
      - Organizaciones Antimperialistas del Caribe y Centroamérica
        - 2nd Congress and Extraordinary Session (1986: Managua) (Box-folder 119: 9)
        - 3rd Plenary Assembly (1988: Panama) (Box-folder 119: 10)
    - Mexico
      - Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores relations with the SWP, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 119: 11)
      - Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores reports on the SWP and El Salvador work, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 119: 12)
    - New Caledonia. Susanna Ounei, For Kanak Independence: The Fight against French Rule in New Caledonia, 1985 (Box-folder 120: 1)
    - New Zealand
      - Socialist Action League debate on labor party, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 120: 2)
      - Socialist Action League debate on women's liberation, 1983 (Box-folder 120: 3)
    - Nicaragua
      - Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional (FSLN) program, 1969 (Box-folder 120: 4)
      - FSLN political report, 1979 (Box-folder 120: 5)
      - SWP debate on Nicaragua, 1984 (Box-folder 120: 6)
        Jack Barnes notes
      - SWP delegation to FSLN anniversary celebration, 1986 (Box-folder 120: 7)
      - Correspondence with FSLN, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 120: 8)
      - Larry Seigle speeches on history of FSLN, Oberlin, Ohio, 1988 (Box-folder 120: 9)
      - Barricada internacional. Correspondence re printing, 1988 (Box-folder 120: 10)
      - Autonomia newsletter. Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 120: 11)
    - Philippines. Russell Johnson draft article, and trip report, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 120: 12)
    - Poland
      - Debate within the SWP, 1981 December (Box-folder 120: 13)
      - Debate within the Fourth International, 1982 January. (Box-folder 120: 14)
        Includes Jack Barnes notes
      - Nat Weinstein correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 120: 15)
      - Debate within the SWP, 1982 February (Box-folder 120: 16)
      - Debate within the Fourth International, 1982 May. (Box-folder 121: 1)
    - Portugal
      - Debate within the Fourth International, 1975 (Box-folder 121: 2)
      - Debate within the Fourth International, 1975 (Box-folder 121: 3)
        Includes Mary-Alice Waters notes
      - Debate within the Fourth International, 1976 (Box-folder 121: 4)
      - SWP resolution and supporting materials, 1976 (Box-folder 121: 5-6)
    - Puerto Rico
      - Movimiento Pro-Independencia/Partido Socialists Puertorriqueño. Reports, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 122: 1)
      - Correspondence with Puerto Rican Trotskyists, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 122: 2)
    - South Africa
      - Trotskyist movement history. Correspondence and articles, 1977-1988 (Box-folder 122: 3)
      - SWP position, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 122: 4)
        Includes Jack Barnes and Mary-Alice Waters notes
      - Neo Mnumzana speeches and correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 122: 5)
      - South African Communist Party documents, 1962-1990. (Box-folder 122: 6)
        Includes writings by Joe Slovo
    - Soviet Union. Articles on its class nature, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 122: 7)
    - Vietnam
      - History, 1920s-1940s (Box-folder 122: 8)
        Articles and notes
      - SWP participation in pro-independence demonstration, 1947 (Box-folder 123: 1)
      - Lists of Militant articles, 1930-1973 (Box-folder 123: 2)
      - George Johnson, "The Vietnamese Communist Party." Book-length typescript, 1973 (Box-folder 123: 3-4)
      - George Johnson and Fred Feldman, "The Vietnamese Communist Party" [revised version]. Typescript, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 124: 1)
      - Debate within the Fourth International, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 124: 2)
      - Vietnam/Cambodia debate, 1979-1980. (Box-folder 124: 3)
      - Debate within the Fourth International, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 124: 4)
      - Steve Clark/Diane Wang speaking tour, 1984 (Box-folder 124: 5)
        Vietnamese press coverage
    - Western Sahara. Articles on Polisario Front, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 124: 6)
    - Zimbabwe. Morgan Tsvangarai correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 124: 7)
  - Individuals File, 1939-1998 (Box 125-128)
    Correspondence, writings, memoranda, notes and printed matter, relating to Socialist Workers Party relations with specific individuals
    - Blanco, Hugo
      - General. Memoranda, press releases and pamphlets, 1967-1982, mainly relating to defense campaigns on behalf of Blanco (Box-folder 125: 1)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1989 (Box-folder 125: 2)
      - Writings by Blanco, 1972-1979. Includes autobiographical writing (Box-folder 125: 3)
    - Deutschmann, David
      - Dispute re legal rights to material published by Ocean Press (Australian company founded by Deutschmann), 1987-1994 (Box-folder 125: 4)
      - Dispute re Ocean Press publication of Che Guevara and the Cuban Revolution, 1995 (Box-folder 125: 5)
      - Cuban press articles re Deutschmann, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 125: 6)
    - Frank, Pierre
      - General. Correspondence and writings, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 125: 7)
      - Speech on history of Fourth International, 1974 (Box-folder 125: 8)
      - Obituaries and memorial meeting, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 9)
    - Gelfand (Alan) lawsuit
      - General, 1976-1989. Mainly printed matter (Box-folder 125: 10)
      - Complaint, findings and notes, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 125: 11)
      - Chronology, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 125: 12)
    - Gilly, Adolfo
      - General. Writings by Gilly, 1977-1983 and undated (Box-folder 125: 13)
      - Guatemala. Correspondence and writings re MR-13 (Movimiento Revolucionario 13 de Noviembre), 1966-1986 (Box-folder 125: 14)
    - Glass, C. Frank
      - General, 1981-1988. (Box-folder 125: 15)
        Includes obituary
      - Correspondence, 1973-1988 (Box-folder 125: 16)
    - Glotzer, Albert. Biographical data and letter, 1976-1990 (Box-folder 126: 1)
    - Gordon, Sam. Correspondence and interview transcript, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 126: 2)
    - Hansen, Joseph
      - General. Biographical data, SWP organizational reports, and introduction to reprint edition of The Militant, 1959-1979 (Box-folder 126: 3)
      - Correspondence
        - Blanco, Hugo, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 126: 4)
        - Frank, Pierre, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 126: 5)
        - Maitan, Livio, 1967-1977 (Box-folder 126: 6)
        - Mandel, Ernest, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 126: 7)
        - Moreno, Nahuel (Hugo), 1965-1975 (Box-folder 126: 8)
      - "All That a Man Has" (novel). Typescript (Box-folder 126: 9-11)
    - Hansen, Reba. Biographical data, Library reorganization, and memorial meeting, 1939-1990 (Box-folder 127: 1)
    - Mandel, Gisela. Correspondence
      - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 127: 2)
      - 1970-1975 (Box-folder 127: 3)
    - Mangan, Sherry
      - Correspondence, 1940-1978 (Box-folder 127: 4)
      - Articles, 1941-1988 (Box-folder 127: 5)
    - Moreno, Nahuel. Jack Barnes and Mary-Alice Waters notes on discussions, circa 1969 (Box-folder 127: 6)
    - Pablo, Michel
      - Correspondence and International Revolutionary Marxist Tendency bulletins and articles
        - 1962-1964 (Box-folder 127: 7)
        - 1971-1982 (Box-folder 127: 8)
      - Interview transcript, 1977 (Box-folder 127: 9)
    - Peng, Shu-tse
      - "The Relationship and Differences between Mao Tse-tung and Liu Shao-chi." Mimeographed bulletin, 1967 (Box-folder 127: 10)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1982 (Box-folder 127: 11)
    - Sakai. Correspondence, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 127: 12)
    - Verla, Catherine. Letter, 1972 (Box-folder 127: 13)
    - Volkov, Esteban. Biographical data, 1970 (Box-folder 127: 14)
    - Willms, Lüko. Correspondence re German translation of Pathfinder Press publications, 1991-1998 (Box-folder 127: 15)
    - Wright, John G.
      - General. Correspondence, writings and memorial tribute, 1944-1956 (Box-folder 127: 16)
      - Speech notes (Box-folder 127: 17)
    - Zugadi, Marcelo
      - Correspondence, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 128: 1)
      - Writings by Zugadi, 1988-1991. (Box-folder 128: 2)
        Includes Panorama antes de la confrontación; 1989 de mayo a agosto; introduction to Fidel Castro pamphlet
      - Miscellany., Articles and pamphlet by Luis Bilbao, CIA-Vaticano: Asociación ilicita (Box-folder 128: 3)
        1989-1992
  - Ernest Mandel File, 1947-1996. (Box 128-134)
    Correspondence, writings and printed matter relating to Socialist Workers Party relations with Ernest Mandel (1923-1995), Belgian economist and Fourth International leader
    - Correspondence. Includes some draft internal documents and other enclosures
      - 1947-1953 (Box-folder 128: 4)
      - 1965-1967 (Box-folder 128: 5)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 128: 6)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 128: 7)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 128: 8)
      - 1971 (Box-folder 128: 9)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 128: 10)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 128: 11)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 129: 1)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 129: 2)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 129: 3)
      - 1977 (Box-folder 129: 4)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 129: 5)
      - 1979-1980 (Box-folder 129: 6)
      - 1982-1983 (Box-folder 129: 7)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 129: 8)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 129: 9)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 129: 10)
    - Speeches and writings, 1948-1995. (Box-folder 130-134)
      Printed copies unless otherwise stated
      - “The True Testament of Trotsky,” Fourth International, 1948 August. (Box-folder 130: 1)
        Typescript (in French) and printed copy
      - “The Third Chinese Revolution,” Fourth International, 1950 September/October-1951 January/February (Box-folder 130: 2)
      - “Eastern Europe since 1950,” Fourth International, 1952 July/August (Box-folder 130: 3)
      - “Economic Problems of Transition Epoch,” Fourth International, 1952 November/December (Box-folder 130: 4)
      - “1903-1953: The Theoretical Sources of the Bolshevik Organization Concept,” Quatrième Internationale, 1953 November. (Box-folder 130: 5)
        Typed English translation
      - “The World Revolution, from Its Empirical Phase to Its Conscious Phase: Remarks on the Fourth World Congress,”, 1954 July. (Box-folder 130: 6)